<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Behavioral on BinHong Lee&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://binhong.me/blog/tags/behavioral/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Behavioral on BinHong Lee&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>binhong@binhong.me (BinHong Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>binhong@binhong.me (BinHong Lee)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://binhong.me/blog/tags/behavioral/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Can Be Both</title>
      <link>https://binhong.me/blog/2025-12-12-you-can-be-both/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>binhong@binhong.me (BinHong Lee)</author>
      <guid>https://binhong.me/blog/2025-12-12-you-can-be-both/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a post arguing that exceptional people are rare because they&amp;rsquo;re so focused on their craft that they skip &amp;ldquo;bureaucratic bullshit&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;often left other skills to rot&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/matsherman_my-take-agree-disagree-would-love-your-activity-7361597201212448769-fQHP/&#34;&gt;I left a comment explaining that it&amp;rsquo;s a 50/50 situation.&lt;/a&gt; In this piece, I&amp;rsquo;ll expand my take on this more in depth. Exceptional people comes in different shapes and forms. Pretending that someone can&amp;rsquo;t be exceptional simply because they learned to deal with the &amp;ldquo;bureaucratic bullshit&amp;rdquo; feels like a weird stereotype. (If anything, this reads like the exact type of mentality that gave birth to the &amp;ldquo;10x engineer&amp;rdquo; meme lol.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is part of a series &lt;a href=&#34;https://binhong.me/blog/2025-05-04-the-opinionated-engineer/&#34;&gt;(The Opinionated Engineer)&lt;/a&gt; where I share my strong opinions on engineering practices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#understanding-the-game&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-game&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Understanding &amp;ldquo;the game&amp;rdquo;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this weird stigma that you&amp;rsquo;re either a technically strong engineer or good at &amp;ldquo;playing politics&amp;rdquo;. These aren&amp;rsquo;t mutually exclusive. In fact, some of the best engineers I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with are good at both because they quickly learned that &amp;ldquo;playing politics&amp;rdquo; is critical to their success so they get good at it while continue to back themselves up with strong technical depths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being good at something doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you love doing it.&lt;/strong&gt; Many of these great engineers would absolutely prefer to just code and solve technical challenges all day rather than spend time in planning meetings, doing stakeholder alignment, or navigating organizational politics. If you gave them the choice, they&amp;rsquo;d pick the technical work every time. But they recognize that in most environments (especially as you grow in seniority), the non-coding work is the best way to &lt;em&gt;scale your impact&lt;/em&gt; so they quickly learned to get good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like pundits complaining about modern NBA playing for the foul calls. These players are still some of the best in the world without it, but they learned that being good at it is critical to their success, so they adapt their game to it. Same thing 20 years ago with the kick-out jumper that Kobe Bryant and Ray Allen did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-is-the-game&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-game&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;the game&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this comes down to understanding what your company / org is biased towards or against in their performance evaluations. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not always what the org needs but mostly what it &lt;em&gt;thinks&lt;/em&gt; it wants. Different orgs has different priorities, speaking with a more senior engineer in the org (or observing more carefully) can show. As an example, certain orgs in Meta has very strong preference for engineers with strong technical skills so you need to be strong code reviewer and technical designer to get (a better chance) at promotion. Others prefer more tech leading skills so you need to show relevant ability - roadmap, plan, drive discussions, create scope - for a better shot at earning that promotion. Some places look for a floor raiser to help them build a 0 -&amp;gt; 1 project; others look for someone who can obsessively optimize mature products to extract maximum value. Generally, there are different archetypes that can earn you the promotion but knowing the &lt;em&gt;preferred archetype&lt;/em&gt; makes it easier for you to get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#play-to-your-strengths&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;play-to-your-strengths&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Play to your strengths&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like if a team signs Messi and makes him play the center back position. I&amp;rsquo;m sure he can still do fine but the team is not getting the most value out of him. Then when it&amp;rsquo;s viewed in vacuum (without context), it&amp;rsquo;d look like he&amp;rsquo;s just an average player. That&amp;rsquo;s you during performance review. Your package is generally reviewed in a vacuum without the context of &amp;ldquo;trying new stuff&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;expanding into new roles&amp;rdquo; (with the exception of joining a new team). Not playing to your strengths hurt both you and the team because the team didn&amp;rsquo;t get the most out of you, while you look like a worse engineer than your capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the org&amp;rsquo;s preferred &lt;em&gt;style&lt;/em&gt; is not something that matches your strength, you&amp;rsquo;d need to consider if putting in the extra work is worth it (maybe you enjoy the people + work enough), or if there are opportunities out there that suit you better. As mentioned before, what the org &lt;em&gt;needs&lt;/em&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily what it &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt;. You can make the case for it but it will take extra effort relative to the alternative. (That said, in many occasions, a successfully made case would allow for better &lt;em&gt;job security&lt;/em&gt; as being the &lt;em&gt;only / few&lt;/em&gt; people with such specialty.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wrap-up&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that you can&amp;rsquo;t be a good engineer if you don&amp;rsquo;t fit your company&amp;rsquo;s performance rubric but rather it&amp;rsquo;d require extra effort from either you or your manager (or both) to make your case. Some are one-offs (defining a new archetype), while others might be recurring (figuring out the right business reason to justify the time and effort on your projects). At some point, you might want to ask yourself if all these extra work is worth the time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also another school of thought that view all these as unnecessary bloats in larger tech companies. I&amp;rsquo;m not here to argue for either (I know, not very opinionated 🫣) but to share what / how to get the most &lt;em&gt;juice&lt;/em&gt; out of your work. Most people like this prefer to stick to startups where performance review processes aren&amp;rsquo;t as rigid. That&amp;rsquo;s valid too. At the end of the day, that&amp;rsquo;s just a different game with different rules. The key is knowing which game you&amp;rsquo;re playing and whether you want to keep playing it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating Effectively</title>
      <link>https://binhong.me/blog/2025-09-19-communicating-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>binhong@binhong.me (BinHong Lee)</author>
      <guid>https://binhong.me/blog/2025-09-19-communicating-effectively/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a common problem at work where you see a problem but you’re having a hard time trying to convince people to support your attempt at fixing it. Worse still, they might not even see it as a problem (or they don’t think it’s something that warrants any attention from anyone). I’m approaching this piece mostly from an &lt;em&gt;“I need my leadership / partners to understand what I do is important”&lt;/em&gt; perspective. But the ideology can similarly be used on other occasions like selling an idea to your peers etc. Ideally you start thinking about this as you try to get the green light to pursue your project instead of attempting to justify it &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you’ve already invested your time into it with little to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is part of a series &lt;a href=&#34;https://binhong.me/blog/2025-05-04-the-opinionated-engineer/&#34;&gt;(The Opinionated Engineer)&lt;/a&gt; where I share my strong opinions on engineering practices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#understand-your-audience&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-your-audience&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Understand your audience&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoever you’re talking to, they have their own perspective and priorities. They care about certain things. Make sure to understand that and position your proposal from &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; perspective. One common communication gap is where someone keeps trying to tell their leaders &lt;em&gt;“how hard they / the team has been working”&lt;/em&gt; - which is cool and all - but your leaders likely want to know more about &lt;em&gt;“what’s in it for me?”&lt;/em&gt;. For example, instead of telling your manager that “I put in 60 hours a week all of last month to make this happen,” it should be more like “I shipped x MAU which is x% of the team / org goal” or “I worked overtime to handle multiple unexpected surprises (have documentation for this) to ensure that we can ship / launch / test {org priority project} in a timely manner.” Changing the framing of your statement (by empathizing with your audience) makes it significantly more appealing to your target audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#strategic-positioning&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;strategic-positioning&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Strategic positioning&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you pitch a project proposal, you need strong reasoning on why you think it will be worth the time investment. In most cases, you’d be making the case using some sort of metrics or goal that the project is expected to improve. However, that’s not always the case. If you have a goal metric to chase but this project doesn’t directly affect that, think of how it’s affected indirectly. In my previous piece on dev tool valuation, I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://binhong.me/blog/2025-07-18-understanding-value-of-dev-tools/#cost-of-engineers&#34;&gt;engineering cost&lt;/a&gt; being the most straightforward measurement available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if there’s a &lt;em&gt;larger org-priority project&lt;/em&gt;, think of how to align your project with it. You might need to make some small changes in the project pitch, but the idea is that you don’t have to build your case from scratch. Instead, you are just piggybacking on an established case by explaining how your project would &lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt; with the goal of completing the larger project. This sort of positioning not only helps reduce the amount of foundational work needed to make people understand the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; but also ensures that your project will continue to receive attention as a side effect of now being associated with the larger project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#reprioritization&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;reprioritization&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Reprioritization&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prioritization changes all the time. When there’s a top-down change in priority, make sure to ask clarifying questions to understand the reasoning behind the shift. From there, you have to then recalibrate your (team’s) projects to make sure they’re still aligned with the higher-level goals. On some occasions, this could also mean that you would have to recommend priority shifts on ongoing / planned projects depending on the leadership goal change. For example, you&amp;rsquo;re in the core infrastructure team and the company decides to pivot to &amp;ldquo;everything AI&amp;rdquo;. Make sure to understand &amp;ldquo;how AI&amp;rdquo; and potentially shift your prioritization around (like adding better GPU support, direct Ollama support etc.) to fit the leadership goal change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#goal-setting&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;goal-setting&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Goal setting&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management (and shareholders) love &lt;em&gt;goals&lt;/em&gt;. They paint a picture of predictability and allow for an easy way to evaluate how you (or the team) are doing. The higher level you get (with bigger scope and projects), the goal would be closer to company-level goals. The hierarchy probably goes something like this: (company-level goal) make more money -&amp;gt; sell more ads -&amp;gt; get more users -&amp;gt; keep existing users returning (team-level goal) etc. You don’t have to set the goal on how to make the company more money, but you can set a goal on how to keep existing users returning which, by proxy, would have your impact cascaded up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wrap-up&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, this is something even I sometimes forget or overlook when pitching a project. The key insight is that effective communication isn’t about having the best technical solution but rather, it&amp;rsquo;s about meeting people where they are and speaking their language. When you frame your ideas through your audience’s priorities and align with existing organizational momentum, you’re offering value in return of their support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
