<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on The Ink Mortar</title><link>https://binhong.me/blog/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on The Ink Mortar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://binhong.me/blog/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to host multiple domain names and projects on one server</title><link>https://binhong.me/blog/2018-08-29-how-to-host-multiple-domain-names-and-projects-on-one-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://binhong.me/blog/2018-08-29-how-to-host-multiple-domain-names-and-projects-on-one-server/</guid><description>I own multiple domain names, and each one hosts a different side project. For the longest time, everything that required ‘hosting’ was hosted on Heroku. But their free tier can be quite limited, it can also get costly quickly if you are paying for each separate project. So instead, I decided to explore putting all of them together using NGINX (recommended to me by Jane Manchun Wong).
Required Resources Virtual Private Server (VPS) You’ll need a virtual server such as DigitalOcean or EC2 by AWS.</description></item><item><title>Hosting your own Git server with Gitea</title><link>https://binhong.me/blog/2018-08-20-hosting-your-own-git-server-with-gitea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://binhong.me/blog/2018-08-20-hosting-your-own-git-server-with-gitea/</guid><description>Most people (including myself) host their personal projects on a third-party free Git hosting websites like GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket etc. While that is sufficient for most people, it is also pretty fun to have your own Git service hosted on your own domain name of choice. While I trust my fellow engineers at these companies, I am using this as a personally backup to those services if anything goes wrong (like GitLab.</description></item></channel></rss>